* I don't ever want to feel *
* 我再也不想有 *
* Like I did that day *
* 如那天般的感受 *
* Take me to the place I love *
* 带我去我爱的地方 *
* Take me all the way *
* 带我一路走 *
* I don't ever want to feel *
* 我再也不想有 *
* Like I did that day *
* 如那天般的感受 *
* Take me to the place I lo...*
* 带我去我爱的地...*
Fellas, please.
伙计们 消停点儿吧
Penny, come on. We were
just finding our sound.
算了吧 Penny 我们刚开始唱呢
You found it. It's the sound of a
cat being run over by a lawn mower.
你自己听听吧 不知道的还以为
哪只猫被卷进割草机里了呢
I'm really very busy.
我真的很忙
Is there any way that we can put this
off until I have more time to prepare?
我们能否推迟一下?
我好有点时间来准备
Of course. But, uh, you
understand my trepidation.
当然了 可... 你知道我有些啥顾虑
- What's that about?
- Not a clue.
- 他又在干嘛?
- 毫无头绪
Can't we just postpone
it till the spring?
就不能推迟到开春吗?
Maybe next summer?
或者明年夏天?
This should be fairly easy to deduce.
这个应该很好推断的
He's holding the phone to his left ear.
他把电话搁在左耳旁边
Ears do not cross hemispheres, so he's using the
analytical rather than the emotional side of the brain,
左耳还是左脑控制的
所以他是在理性分析而不是感情用事
suggesting that he has no personal
relationship with the caller.
表明他和来电者没有私人关系
No, I didn't realize
it had been so long.
不 我没想到已经这么久了
Sure, I guess there's no other
choice but to just go ahead and do it.
好吧 那就只好这么办了
He's referring to an
activity he has done before.
他谈到了一件以前做过的事
It's unpleasant and
needs to be repeated.
那件事不怎么令人愉快
但又不得不再来一遍
This suggests some sort of invasive
medical test, like perhaps a colonoscopy.
表明这件事应该是某种侵入性
医疗检查 比如说 结肠镜检查
Aren't there any other options?
就没有其他选择了么?
There's not a lot of room.
It's gonna be uncomfortable.
没多大地方 肯定很不舒服的
Yes, yes.
没错 没错
I'm definitely going with colonoscopy.
我敢肯定是结肠镜检查
Okay, bye.
好吧 再见
My mother's coming to visit.
我妈要来看我
How about that, you were right.
听听 你说得没错啊
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
-=伊甸园美剧http://sfile.ydy.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:咔肉肉
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: 饭特稀 帆帆 王泳东
校对: penny
时间轴: 咔肉肉
双语:徐小帆
The Big Bang
Theory Season02 Episode15
天才理论传
第二季 第15集
It's out of order.
电梯坏了
Yes, I can read the sign. I'm
just pondering the implications.
嗯 我识字的 我只是在沉思
其背后的深意
I think it implies that
the elevator doesn't work.
我觉得这意味着电梯不工作了
Again, I can read the sign.
再说一遍 我识字的
But the sign and the tape are
coated with a layer of dust,
不过标签和胶带上都有厚厚一层灰了
which indicates that the elevator has been
nonfunctional for a significant amount of time.
这表示电梯已经坏了
有相当长的一段时间了
Which suggests either a
remarkable passivity among the,
也就暗示着这栋大楼里的
I assume, 24 to 36
residents of this building,
大约24到36位居民十分不主动
based on the number of mailboxes and
given typical urban population density
噢 居民数我是从邮箱的数目以及
普通城镇人口密度推断出来的
or a shared delusion of functionality.
或者说这些人都有功能性错觉
You must be Leonard's mother.
你一定是Leonard他母亲
Oh, I don't know if I must be, but yes.
噢 不知道是不是非得是 不过是的
Uh, I'm Penny. I'm his neighbor.
我是Penny 他的邻居
Oh, Dr. Beverly Hofstadter.
噢 Beverly Hofstadter博士
Oh, nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你
Oh, you're a hand shaker. Interesting.
噢 你习惯握手啊 真有趣
Uh, why don't you come with me.
I'll walk you to the apartment.
你跟我一起走吧 我带你去他们房间
Oh, all right. Would you like to
exchange pleasantries on the way?
噢 好啊 路上咱先寒暄寒暄吧?
- Yeah, sure, I guess.
- All right, you start.
- 嗯 好啊
- 那好 你先说吧
Okay. You know, I've
always been curious.
行 你要知道 我一直都好奇心很重
What was Leonard like
when he was little?
Leonard小时候是什么样的?
Oh, I think you mean young.
He's always been little.
噢 我想你是指他年轻的时候
他一直都是个小不点儿
Right, okay. What was he
like when he was young?
没错 他年轻的时候是什么样的?
You'll have to be more specific.
你得再说具体点儿
Um, okay, like, five or six.
呃... 好吧 比如说 五六岁的时候
Five.
五岁
Oh, well, at that age, he was well enmeshed in what Freud
would call the phallic stage of psychosexual development.
那时他正深陷于弗洛伊德所谓的
心理性发展之生殖器崇拜阶段
An outmoded theory, of course, but the
boy did spend most of his waking hours
当然是个过时的理论了
不过那孩子确实在大部分醒着的时候
with a tight grasp on his penis.
牢牢地抓住自己的小弟弟不放
Yeah, Leonard mentioned
you were a psychiatrist.
是啊 Leonard说起过 你是个精神病学家
Well, that is one of my degrees.
My primary field is neuroscience.
那只是其中一个学位罢了
我主要涉及的领域是神经系统学
Well, I'm an actress.
我是个演员
Why?
为什么?
What do you mean why?
什么叫为什么?
Well, there are studies
that suggest that many
有研究表明
who go into the performing arts suffer
from an external locus of identity.
许多演艺界的人士都有外控性格
Yeah, I don't know what that means.
我不知道你在说什么
Well, it means you value
yourself only as others value you,
是说当别人重视你时 你才会重视自己
which is often the result of
unmet childhood emotional needs.
通常是童年未满足的情感需求导致的
Oh, well, I had a wonderful childhood.
噢 我的童年可了不得了
Tell me about it.
是么
I know my dad wanted a boy.
我知道老爸想要个儿子
I-I just, I tried being good at
sports, but I hated getting dirty!
我... 我努力让自己变成体育健将
可我真的讨厌把自己弄脏!
And then, I'm assuming,
you entered adolescence.
然后 我想你进入了青春期
He called me Slugger until
I got my first training bra.
在我得到第一件运动内衣之前
他都管我叫"重击手"来着
And then he just stopped
playing catch with me.
之后他就不和我玩传接球了
I wasn't Slugger anymore.
我再也不是"重击手"了
Your mother's here!
你妈妈来了!
If y w want to have intercouee with tt t girl,
find out what kind of cologne her fathorore.
如果你想和那个姑娘上床
查查他老爸擦的是哪种古龙水
Good to see you, Mother.
见到你真好 妈妈
Here's your tea, Mother.
这是你要的茶 妈妈
- Oolong?
- Yes.
- 乌龙茶?
- 嗯
- Loose, not bagged?
- Yes.
- 散装的 不是袋泡的?
- 嗯
- Steeped three minutes?
- Yes.
- 泡了三分钟?
- 嗯
- Two-percent
milk? - Yes.
- 加了2%的牛奶
- 嗯
- Warmed separately?
- Yes.
- 分开加热的?
- 嗯
- One teaspoon sugar?
- Yes.
- 一茶勺糖?
- 嗯
- Raw sugar?
- Yes.
- 原糖?
- 嗯
It's cold.
凉了
I'll start again.
我再来一回
I*******
我也有同样的困扰
*******developed sex drive.
我的看法是他无法集中精力
是因为过度发达的性冲动造成的
Oh, I don't know where
he would've gotten that.
他怎么会有那玩意儿
Aside from a pro forma
consummation of our marriage,
除却一段形式上完满的婚姻
his father and I only had intercourse
for the purposes of reproduction.
他的父亲和我交髯只是为了繁殖
That seems a fairly
efficient arrangement.
这样还真是高效哈
Yes, we think so. We've
both done papers on it.
是啊 我们也这么想
我们曾为这事做了论文研究
Mine from the neuroscientific point of
view and his from an anthropological.
我从神经系统科学观点出发
他是从人类学观点出发
Mine, of course, was the
only one worth reading.
当然 我的才有阅读价值
Of course.
当然
I would very much like to
read about your sex life.
我非常希望可以拜读一下你的性生活
Well, it's all online or you can order
it from the Princeton University Press.
你可以在线阅读或者
你可以从普林斯顿大学出版社订购
Here's your tea, Mother.
这是你的茶 妈妈
So, what are you guys talking about?
你们在聊什么呢?
The frequency with which
your parents had intercourse.
你父母性交的频率
Swell.
哦
If you're lucky, maybe she'll show
you the PowerPoint presentation.
幸运的话 她会给你做幻灯片演讲哦
I'm sorry, it's on my other laptop.
对不起 那在我另一个笔记本里
So, Mother... what's new?
妈妈... 有什么新鲜事?
You'll have to be more specific.
你应该要有针对性地问
All right. Uh, what's new with you?
好吧 你有什么新鲜事?
Oh, well, I've been having some
fascinating menopausal symptoms recently.
哦 我最近有一些令人着迷的
更年期征兆
Maybe something less personal.
说些不是太私人的事
Your Uncle Floyd died.
你Floyd叔叔死了
Oh, my God. What happened?
哦 天啊 出什么事了?
His heart stopped beating.
他的心脏不跳了
I have to urinate.
我得去小便
What a remarkable woman.
多么非凡的女人
Yeah, I-I thought you
guys might hit it off.
是啊 我就觉着你俩合得来
I envy you your childhood.
我很嫉妒你的童年
I hate to tell you, but the only warm memories
I have of my childhood are of my Uncle Floyd.
不想这么说 但我童年时期唯一
温暖的记忆都是来自我Floyd叔叔
You're clearly misremembering.
你很显然记错了
Your mother is brilliant,
analytical, insightful.
你妈妈太有才了 既有分析能力
又富有洞察力
And I'm betting she never hit you with a Bible
because you wouldn't eat your Brussels sprouts.
而且我打赌她不会因为
你不吃芽甘蓝 就用圣经来打你
Sheldon, you don't give
your mother enough credit.
Sheldon 你太不会欣赏你妈妈了
She's warm, she's loving,
她很温暖 她很慈爱
she doesn't glue electrodes to your head to
measure your brain waves while potty training.
不会在你学用婴儿便盆时
就把电极粘到你头上来测脑电波
You were lucky.When I was
a kid, if I wanted an EEG,
够有福了 我小的时候
要是想做脑电图
I had to attach my own electrodes.
我还得自己接电极
So, Dr.Hofstadter, Leonard rarely talks about
his incredibly successful brother and sister.
Hofstadter博士 Lenoard很少谈起
他格外成功的兄弟姐妹
Please, don't go there, Howard.
求你 别说起这个 Howard
I understand that, unlike Leonard, they're
at the top of their respective fields.
我知道 不像Lenoard
他们在各自的领域里是尖子
Boy, you suck.
兄弟 你很烦
Well, Leonard's younger brother, Michael,
is a tenured law professor at Harvard,
Leonard的弟弟 Michael
是哈佛大学的终身制法学教授
and his sister just successfully grew a
human pancreas in an adolescent gibbon.
他姐姐刚在一个青年长臂猿身上
成功地培育了一个人类的胰腺
So, she's close to curing diabetes?
说来 她就快能治糖尿病了?
Why else would you grow a
pancreas in a enaged gibbon?
要不然为啥在青年长臂猿身上培育胰腺?
Wow, you must be very proud.
哇喔 你肯定对此感到很骄傲
Why? They're not my accomplishments.
骄傲啥 又不是我的成就
I have to urinate.
我得去小便
Why are you doing this?
为什么你要这么做?
You know the rules. You brought
your mom to work-- you must suffer.
你知道规矩 你带妈妈来上班
就等着遭罪吧
Leonard, I had no idea your siblings
were so much more successful than yo
Leonard 真不知道你兄妹
比你强那么多呢呀
Yeah, you're like the Jar Jar
Binks of the Hofstadter family.
你就像Hofstadter家族的加・加・宾克斯
(星战人物 笨手笨脚)
Oh, meesa think yousa lookin' so so sad.
哦~我呀觉得你呀看起来好伤心哟
You know, rather than mock me, my friends
might realize that this is difficult
比起嘲笑我 我的朋友们应该
意识到我这日子不好过
and try to help me through it.
并试着帮我渡过难关
Nope, I think mocking you isore fun.
不 我认为嘲笑你更有意思
Next time, don't yousa
bring mama to work. Okee-day?
下次 你呀来带妈妈来工作不?
That was fast.
很快啊
Oh, the middle stall was occupied.
I'll have to try again later.
哦 中间那个隔间有人 我一会再去
That's totally understandable.
这是完全可以理解的
In bladder voiding, as in real estate,
it's location, location, location.
在膀胱排泄过程中 就好比房地产
最重要的就是位置 位置 还是位置
So, where were we?
我们说到哪了?
Howard lives with his mother and Raj
can't speak to women unless he's drunk.
Howard和他妈妈一起住
Raj只有喝醉了才和女人讲话
Go.
开讲吧
That's fascinating. Selective
mutism is quite rare.
真有意思 选择性缄默症是非常罕见的
On the other hand, an adult
Jewish male living with his mother
另一方面 一个成年犹太男人
跟他的妈妈住在一起
is so common it borders
on sociological clich\.
就太常见了 社会学中家常便饭
It's just temporary; I pay rent.
只是暂时的 我有付租金
He lives in the same room
where his bassinet was.
他的摇篮还放在自己的卧室
You know, both selective mutism and an
inability to separate from one's mother
选择性缄默症和无法跟妈妈分开
can stem from a
pathological fear of women.
都可能源于对女性的病态恐惧
It might explain why the two of you have
created an ersatz homosexual marriage
可以解释你俩为什么假装同性结婚
to satisfy your need for intimacy
来满足你们对亲热的需求
Say what?
说啥?
That's basically what I just said.
不就是我刚说的嘛
You brought your husband
to work. You know the rules.
你带老公来上班 你知道规矩的
Meesa thinking yousa looking
pretty sad now too, betcha, betcha.
我呀觉得你呀看起来也很伤心哟
真的哟 真的哟
Leonard, it's 1:00.
Leonard 1点了
Weren't you going to show
me your laboratory at 1:00?
你不是要在1点带我去实验室么?
There's no hurry, Mother.
不用着急 妈妈
Tell them more about their
secret love for each other.
再跟他们讲讲他们的爱恋之情
But it's 1:00. You were going to
show me your laboratory at 1:00.
但是1点了啊 你说1点带我看实验室的
Her reasoning is
unassailable It is 1:00.
她完全在理啊 1点了
Fine. Let's go.
好吧 走吧
I think you'll find my
work pretty interesting.
你会觉得我的工作特别有意思
I'm attempti to replicate the dark matter signal
found in sodium iodide crystals by the Italians.
我试图复制意大利人曾发现的
钠的碘化物结晶上黑物质信号
So, no original research?
不是原创的研究喽?
No.
不是
Well, what's the point of my seeing it?
那还有啥好参观的
I could just read the
paper the Italians wrote.
看意大利人写的文章不得了
Just for the record, we're not in
an ersatz homosexual relationship.
告诉你哦 我们不是什么假同性恋人
Wellthen why didn't you say that to her?
那你刚才怎么不跟她说?
Why is it always my responsibility?
怎么总是怪我啊?
It's not always your responsibility.
啥总是怪你啊
I swear, this is the same thing you
did at the comic book store last week.
我发誓 上周在漫画书店
你也是这么干的
I can't believe you're bringing that up.
你居然敢提起这事
I didn't bring it up. You did.
我没提 是你提的
We'll talk about this later.
咱们过会再说
You always say that, but we never do.
你老是这么说 可是从来也没谈
You went to the comic
book store without me?
你们去漫画书店 竟然没带我
You got alcohol?
你有酒么?
- Your mom still here?
- Yep.
- 你妈妈还在这呢?
- 是啊
Come on in.
进来吧
Wait, wait, she's not gonna come
here looking for you, is she?
等等 她不会过来找你吧?
Relax. She took Sheldon to the
hospital to get a brain scan.
放心吧 她带Sheldon
去医院扫描大脑了
Oh, my God. What happened?
天啦 出什么事了?
Nothing. Mother likes looking at brains
and Sheldon likes getting his brain scanned.
没事 老妈喜欢看大脑
Sheldon喜欢大脑被扫描
Geez, what a fun couple.
呀 多搭调的一对呀
She's only been here a day and a half and I'm
seriously considering alcoholism as a new career path.
她才来一天半
我已经在考虑当职业酗酒者了
Hey, I talked to her for five minutes
yesterday and I've been half bombed ever since.
嘿 我昨天和她谈了五分钟
我到现在还没缓过神来呢
You can't let her get into your head.
千万别往脑子里去
My head, what about yours?
我的脑子 你的呢?
It's too late for me. My
head is her summer house.
我没救了 我脑袋已是她的避暑别墅了
She was right, you know.
她说的对
The locus of my identity
is totally exterior to me.
我还真是外控性格
Oh, yeah, there she is. Hi, Mom.
是呀 老妈上身了 老妈 你好
I mean, do you know
where I was all morning?
你知道我整个早上在哪儿吗?
Auditioning with 50 other blondes for
some stupid antidepressant commercial.
为某傻傻的抗抑郁药品广告
和50个金发美女试镜
And for what?
为了啥?
So I'll finally get my daddy's approval?
为了最终获得我爸的认可?
Did you get the part?
你得到角色了吗?
No, they said I was too perky.
没 他们觉得我太活泼了
You want to talk about not
getting love from a parent.
想谈谈得不到父母关爱么
You know what I used to do when I was little
to have some sensation of human contact?
你知道我小时候 为了感知
人情味而干了什么吗?
Yeah, you grabbed your
penis and wouldn't let go.
知道 你抓住小弟弟不放
Your mother told me.
你妈告诉我的
Of course she did. Anyway,
that's not what I was gonnaay.
肯定是她说的 不过
那不是我想说的
When I was ten years old,
I built a hugging machine.
我十岁的时候 我造了个拥抱机
- A hugging machine?
- Yeah.
- 拥抱机?
- 是呀
I got a dressmaker's mannequin,
我有个做裁缝用的模特
I stuffed it with an electric
blanket so it would be warm,
我塞进一床电热毯 让它变得温暖
and built two radio-controlled arms
that would hug me and pat my back.
又造了无线电控制的双臂
可以拥抱我 轻拍我的背
Oh, that is so sad.
呀 可怜的孩子
- You know what the saddest part was?
- What?
- 知道最可怜的是什么吗?
- 什么?
My father used to borrow it.
我爸常借过去用
Your scan data will be
very helpful to my research.
你的扫描数据会对
我的研究很有帮助
You have a remarkable brain.
你的大脑很与众不同
I know.
我知道
Although I've always hated how my
right frontal lobe looks in pictures.
尽管我一直很不喜欢我右额叶图
Common complaint among men.
男人的常见抱怨
Nothing's ever big enough.
什么都嫌不够大
Except when they get a tumor.
Then you never hear the end of it.
除非得了肿瘤 要不总是抱怨
I'd love to e a scan
of your brain sometime.
有机会我很想看看你的脑扫描图
Oh, I'll send you a link, but its
physiology is fairly unimpressive.
我会给你发个链接
但其生理机能比较稀疏平常
Oh, I can't believe that.
不会吧
Your unwillingness to accept empirical
evidence suggests an attempt at flattery.
你不愿接受经验证据
显示出你打算对我阿谀奉承
My apologies.
我很抱歉
I've been living with your son too
long. Gotten into some bad habits.
长期与你儿子居住 养成了一些坏习惯
Understandable.
可以理解
Can I make you a cup of tea?
我能为你沏杯茶吗?
I doubt it, but if anyone has
a chance, it's probably you.
我不太确定 但是如果
有人可以的话 可能就是你
I feel very comfortable around you.
和你相处我十分自在
I feel very comfortable around you, too.
和你相处我也很自在
It's surprising because I generally don't
feel comfortable around, well, anyone.
令人吃惊的是
我基本上和谁相处都...不自在
Nor I.
我也是
What are the odds that two individuals
as unique as ourselves would be connected
我们两个这样如此稀罕的人
by someone as comparatively
workaday as your son?
被像你儿子这般普通的人
联系起来的可能性有多大呀?
Is that a rhetorical point or
would you like to do the math?
你是在比喻还是想算出来?
I'd like to do the math.
我想算出几率来
I'd like that, too.
我也是
Okay, now this time, you're
gonna lick the salt...
好啦 这次 你要舔掉...
off my neck...
我脖子上的盐...
do the shot... Whoops.
干一杯...哟
and then bite the lime.
然后咬住酸橙
I'm sorry, I didn't hear
anything after "lick."
抱歉 "舔"字后面的完全没清
Neck, shot, lime.
脖子 干杯 酸橙
- Okay, shot, lime.
- Right.
- 好啦 干杯 咬酸橙
- 对
Where's the lime?
酸橙呢?
Oh, okay, we're sharing.
好极了 我们一起吃吧
So, what do you think?
那么 你觉得如何?
I'm very tempted.
相当的诱人
I'm just not sure it's
appropriate with my son's roommate.
我不知道与我儿子的室友
这么做 是否合适
Normally, I'd feel the same way.
通常 我也这样想
But based on everything
I've observed about us,
但基于我所观察到的我们之间的情况
I can't help but speculate
we'd be very good together.
我不得不推测我们一起会相当得棒
True. I've had a similar observation.
对 我也观察到了
It's certainly something I
could never do with my husband.
我和我丈夫永远也不会发生这事
I was hesitant the
first time I tried it,
我第一次尝试的时候也很犹豫
but I experienced an unanticipated
anremarkable release of endorphins.
但我经历了一次前所未有的
极量"快感荷尔蒙"释放
It's quite satisfying.
相当的惬意呀
I see what you're doing.
我明白你想干什么
You're appealing to the
neuroscientific researcher in me.
你请求对我做一次神经学研究
You see right through me, don't you?
你能看透我 对吧?
Only when you're in a CAT scanner.
只有在分层造影扫描机里才行
This is actually gonna happen.
美梦正在成真呀
Honey, shush, shush,
shush, shush, shush.
宝贝 嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘
You shush, I'm happy.
I want to talk about it.
你别出声 我乐死了 我想谈谈
You know what my mother
would say about this?
知道我妈会怎么说吗?
She would say because you were not loved by
your father and I was not loved by my mother,
她会说因为你缺父爱 而我缺母爱
that having sex is our way of making up
for the intimacy we didn't get as children.
我们做爱是为了弥补
我们童年缺少的亲人之爱
Why would you bring that up right now?
为啥你现在提起这个?
I don't know. Foreplay?
不知道也 作为前戏?
So you're saying you're not having sex
with me, you're having sex with your mother?
你的意思是你不是和我做爱
是而你妈做了?
I'm gonna go with "no."
我想说的是"不是"
That is the sickest
thing I've ever heard.
这是我听过的最变态的事
Come on, you're trying to have sex with
your father, and I'm okay with that.
别呀 如果你想和你爸做爱
我没意见的
Get out!
滚出去!
She said shush. I should have shushed.
她说嘘的时候 我就该闭嘴
Ooh, all night, all night
彻夜 彻夜
Oh, every night
每夜
Hold tight
抱紧
You hold tight
你抱紧
Baby, hold tight
宝贝儿 抱紧吧
Anyway you want it,
that's the way you need it
你想怎样 就怎样
Anyway you want it...
你想怎样...
All right, Mother.
好啦 妈妈
Um, have a nice flight.
一路平安
That's not really in my control, is it?
不由我说了算 对吧?
Oh, uh, yes.
哦 对了
Oh, good morning.
早上好
Morning.
早
Look, I was just coming
over to talk to you.
我正想过来和你谈谈
You don't have to. Ever.
你用不着谈了 永远别
Gotcha.
知道了
- Good-bye, Mother.
- Good-bye, Leonard.
- 再见 妈妈
- 再见 Leonard
So, Slugger, shall we pick up
where we left off last time?
重击手 我们接着聊上次的话题吗?
I mean, my mom could've just said,
Bob, get over it, she's a girl, move on.
我是说 我妈可以说 Bob 算了吧
她是个女孩子 日子还得过
But she didn't. Not one word.
但她没有 口都没张
Interesting.
有意思
Would you be willing to fly to New Jersey and
discuss your relationship with your parents
你愿意到新泽西聊聊
你和父母的关系
during a brain scan?
与此同时做脑扫描吗?
- Would it help?
- Well, it would help me.
- 对我有帮助吗?
- 嗯 对我有帮助